<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-lizzie-borden</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024546/1892-08-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Fall+River+Borden+Lizzie+Andrew+Sullivan+Bridget+Churchill&st=image&r=-0.245,-0.074,1.49,1.49,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MAN AND WIFE KILLED
And Not One Clew Left by Which the
Murderer Can Be Traced.
A MILLIONAIRE MILL OWNER
And His Faithful Spouse Assassinated in
Their Own KTrellinj.
HORRIBLE DISCOVER! OP A DAUGHTER
SPECIAL TELEOHAJI TO TITE DISPATCn.l
Fall Bivin, Mass., Aug. 4. Andrew
J. Borden, the millionaire mill owner, and
his aged wife were murdered in tbelr home,
to-day, just before noon, and, although there
were other members of the family on the
premises at the time, they heard no sound,
and the murderer escaped without leaving a
clew, so far as is known, although his cloth
ing must have been covered with the blood
of his victims.
The boldness of the crime and the -utter
absence of any apparent motive make It the
morer mysterious. At 11 o'clock Mr. Borden
was lying on the lounge in his sitting room
Teading a newspaper. He was seen by his
daughter Lizzie as she'passed through the
room on her way to the bart-to get ajuece
ot iron with which to mend a flower
pot The servant, Bridget Sullivan,
passed through the room at the same
time, with a pail of water in her hand.
She was on her way to the second floor to
clean windows. Mrs. Borden was In her
room over1 the parlor changing her dress
preparatory to making a visit te sick neigh
bors. A Daughter's Horrible Discovery.
Fifteen minntes later Miss Borden re
entered the house, and when she stepped
through the doorway into the sitting room
she saw her father's body horribly muti
lated and lying in a pool of blood by the
side of the lounge. She was overwhelmed
by the sight. Then she screamed for help.
"Bridget Sullivan was washing a window
in a rear room, but she lost no time in run
ning to Miss Borden's aid. Mrs, Churchill,
a neighbor, also heard the scream, and she
hastened to the house. She entered the
house by the front way, and the servant
commanded all approaches to the honse
from the rear, but neither saw anyone leav
ing'the house.
Miss Borden then called for her mother,
but received no response. She ran upstairs
to her mother's room and fainted when she
opened the door. Her mother had been
murdered in the same brutal manner, her
sknll being crushed in by some heavy in
strument, apparently an ax. Mrs. Borden
had been brained by the back of the ax,
and, in addition, had been hacked with the
sharp edge until her head was chopped to
pieces.
Both rooms in which tbe murders had
been committed were bespattered with
blood, but showed no signs of a struggle.
No attempt at robbery had been made.
Kot a Clew to the Blnrderer.
Who the murderer was, why he committed
the crime, or where he went, are tbe ques
tions which the police would like to solve,
but thus far they have found nothing that
can help them. They have arrested three
persons on suspicion, but the only sus
picious circumstances about them was the
fact that they were seen in the neighbor
hood about the hour of tbe murder.
Mr. Borden was a very large owner of
real estate in Fall Eiver. Charles a Cook
was his agent collecting his rents, and yes
terday paid to the old gentleman a large
snm of money from his rentals.- He made
regular deposits in the Union Bank, and
never paid any accounts except by check.
He left home as usual, about 9 o'clock
this morning, to take bis de
posit to the bank. About 10:30
o'clock his deposit Mas received at tbe
Union Bank, and be went from there to his
home, arriving about 10:40 o'clock and
going into the sitting room to recline upon
the lounge and read the newspaper. Mrs.
Borden went upstairs to make the bed in
the bedroom in the front of the house. No
one except the murderer saw them after
ward until the dead bodies were found.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1892-08-12/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BORDEN+LIZZIE+Borden+Lizzie&r=-0.415,0.003,1.607,0.666,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>cTrra nr.rnnr. ttth ATinr.ST.
Tho day's proceedings began early this
morning with a conforenco botween Chief ot
Police Hilliard. District Attorney Enowlton.
and Medical Examiner Dolan. This consulta
tion lasted until after 10 o'clock. Then Dr.
Dolan hurriedly drove away. The inquest
began at 11 o'clock. Tho first witness called
was Mrs. Josonhine Tripp from West port She
has known Lizzie Borden from n small child.
Thoy wont to school together and wero always
warm friends.
Mrs. Tripp was questioned chlofly in rogard
to her knowledge of the domestic, relations
botween Lizzie Bordon nnd hor father and
stepmother. It is said that this confirmod and
strengthened tho testimony alroady elvon by
other wltnoesos. and which shows that bo
tween Lizzie and hor paronts thero was a
fooling of unfriendliness, if not dislike Whon
nskod about Lizzlo horsolt, as eho know her.
Mrs. Tripp Bald that she was a firm, deter
mined girl, very conservative, and of strong
will.
Tho noxt witness aftor Mrs. Tripp was C. L,
Sawyer of this city. Mr. Sawyor was ono of
tho first pooplo to roaoh tho house after
Bridget Sullivan ran across the streot scream
ing for Dr. Bowon. He wont in through the
sldo door, nnd saw Mr. Bordon lying dead on
tho sitting-room sofo. Ho was questioned
first in regard to the time. He said that
he passed the house first about 11:10
o'clock, and that then tho Sullivan
girl wns coming out aftor Dr. Bowen. Ho ran
Into tho yard. He was suro It was not later
than 11:14 o'clock whon Dr. Bowon came
across tho street on tho run. Tim noxt wit
ness was Mrs. Porry Gttford. Sho has known
tho IJSrdon girls for years nnd was at the
houso soon aftor the murdor. Tho question of
tho hoitilo focling said to havo existed bo
twoon Lizzlo Bordon and tho murdored
couplo was put to hor. Hor answer did
not nry from or contradict those of
previous witness, who swore that thero
was much unfrlondllnoss botwoon thorn. About
Lizzlo herself sho exprcesod practically tho
same opinion as that sworn to by Mrs. Tripp.
Mrs. GIITord loft tho room about 12 o'clock,
and was followod in tho witness stand by Mrs.
Bertha Whitehead, a sister of Mrs. Bordon, the
murdorod woman. It was lcarnod that Mrs.
Whitehead's tostimony was ospeclally valua
ble. In that It quotod BDecltlo Instances where
tho alleged hat rod ot LIzilo Bordon for her
paronts cropped out,
Mrs. Whitehead explained among other
thingsthnt sho formorly owned a houso in con
junction with another person. Tho other per
son mortgaged hor Intorost and tho mort
gage was foreclosed, Mr. Bordon bought it,
gae It to Mrs. Whitehead, and established hor
title to tho proporty, It was lcarnod further
that Lizzlo Bordon Is said to havo objocted
strongly to this, and to have blamed her step
mother for porhttadlng Mr. Bordon to part with
somoof Ills money,
TESTIMONY nFUUDlNO FAnKONB.
After Mrs. Whitehead had testified further
in rogard to less important matters, tho wit
nesses wero sont home, and the District At
torney and the Chief ot Pollco hold another
consultation,
At Its closo both men went to dinnor. It was
decided dollnltoly, however, at this conferonce
to summon Lizzie Borden before Judge Blals
doll at tho afternoon session, and, unless
something unexpected prevented, place her
under arrest at tho close of the session.
Tho afternoon session began at 2:30 o'olock.
The first witness called was Eli Benso, the
clerk in Dr. Smith's drug storo, who told tho
pollco several days ago that Lizzie Bordan had
tried to purohase poison at Mr. Smith's drug
store.
Benco swore to this statement and It Is said
guva fuithar information which materially
strongthons that part of the evidence against
Lizzie Bordon, which rolatos to the poisoning.
Aftor tho testimony of Bonco had been
taken, a drug clerk named Frank Rllroy was
called. It wns learned that Kllroy lsonoot
tho witnesses by whom tho District Attornoy
Is going to provo that Lizzlo Borden not
only trlod to purchase but actually did buy
poison. Whon Kllroy was through. Cashier
Fred Hart ot tho Union Bovine Bank, In which
Mr. Bordon Is said to havo kopt his stocks nnd
bonds, went up stairs to tho courtroom. Mr.
Hnrt was nsked In regard to Mr. Borden's
financial affairs.
It has beon proved that tho suscocted poi
sonous milk drank by tho Bordon family was
all rlgnt when It was takon from tho Bordon.
farm aud brought to this city. Mombors ot
the family in charge ot tho form drank It and
thoy woro affoctcd In no notlceablo way.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024546/1892-08-12/ed-1/?sp=1&q=murder+Arrested+Borden+Lizzie&r=-0.232,0.096,1.237,0.513,0</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>Lizzie Borden Arrested for
the Murder of Her Rich
Father and Mother.
AS COOL AS A CUCUMBER.
She Waives the Heading of the War
rant and Is Locked Up.
A GIRL OP WOX ffERYE AND WILL
The Police Certain They Have Made K
luitalce.in the Matter.
A DRAMATIC BCEXE IN THE TEAGEDI
CSFZCUX. TZLXOBAM TO THX DISPATCH. 1
Pall BrvEB, Mass., Aug, 1L The Bor.
den murder mystery, according to the belief
of the police, is solved. At 7:10 o'clock to
night Lizzie Borden was arrested, accused of
homicide. For one week the police and
other proper authorities have labored un
remittingly to fasten the crime upon the
perpetrator. They believe to-night that
they have done it
The Iron nerve 'and wonderful self-control
of the accused womac was never mora
clearly manifested than when the warrant
charging her with the murder of her
parents was read to her this
evening: This same woman, who
yesterday seemed about to give away
to her emotion, stood silent and motionless,
without a tremor, when Chief of Police
Hilliard entered the Borden mansion to
serve the warrant upon her. Chief Hilliard
tore open the envelope, unfolded the war
rant and began to read.
Lawyer Jennings, attorney for the sisters,
rose and said: "Mr. Marshal, I think my
client will waive the reading of the war
rant" The Girl ns Cool as a Cncnmber".
"Do you waive such reading?" asked
Chief Hilliard of Lizzie.
The woman was silent for a moment; then
she turned to her lawyer.
"Answer him," said he.
"I waive further reading on that paper,"
she said.
There was no false note in the voice, she
did not falter and there was no trace of
nervousness. She stood cold and silent for
a second. Only her lips trembled. Then
her jaws shut with a snap and she sank
back in her chair.
"You are placed in the hands of Matron
Bussell," said Marshal Hiliard, as he left the
room. Miss Emma Borden arose and turned
to her sister. For a minute they stood face
to face, then the olderwoman hurried down
stairs, followed by Lawyer Jennings
and Mrs. Brigham. Downstairs a great
throngs urged to and fro. They filled the
streets, choked into the hall, and even
forced their way into the main room of the
building.
As Miss Emma Borden entered this roora
the crowd blocked the way ahead of her5r
She stopped and clutched the arm of Mrs.
Brigham, and her eyes were full of tears.
A reporter approached her and asked her
if she had anything to say.
The Sister Has Nothing to Say.
"What can I say?" she asked, plead
ingly.
The inquest began at 11 o'clock. The
first witness called was Mrs. Josephine
Tripp, from Westport She has known Lizzie
Borden from childhood. It is said she
confirmed the testimony already given by
other witnesses, and which shows that be
tween Lizzie and her parents there was a
feeling of unfriendliness, if not of dislike.
The next witness, Colonel Sawyer,
of this city, was one of the first
people to reach the house after
the discovery of the tragedy.
He was questioned first in regard to the
time. He was sure it was not later than
11:15 when Dr. Bowen came across the
street on the run.
No Love Lost Between Them.
To the next witness, Mrs. Perry Gifford,
the question of the hostile feeling said to
have existed between Lizzie Borden and the
murdered couple was put Her answer did
not contrdict those of previous witnesses.
Mrs. Giflbrd was followed by Mrs. Bertha
Whitehead, a sister of Mrs. Borden. Mrs.
Whitehead quoted specific instances where
the alleged hatred of Lizzie Borden for her
parents cropped out Mrs. Whitehead
explained, among other things, that
she formerly owned a house in conjunction
with another person. The other person
mortgaged her intetest and the mort
gage was foreclosed. 'Mr. Borden
bought it and gave it to Mrs.
Whitehead, and established her title
to the property. It was learned further
that Lizzie Borden is said to have objected
strongly to this, and to have blamed her
stepmother for persuading Mr. Borden to
part with some of his money.
Attempts to Purchase Poison.
After Mrs. Whitehead had testified, the
District Attorney and tHe Chief of Police
held another long consultation. At its
close both men went to dinner. It
was decided at this conference
to summon Lizzie Borden before
Judge Blalsdell at the afternoon session,
and unless something unexpected prevented,
place her under arrest
The afternoon session began at 2:30
o'clock. Eli Bense, the drug clerk who
told the police that Lizzie Borden had
tried to nnrchase poison, swore to
this. Another drug clerk, Frank
Kilroy, was called up. Kilroy Is one of the
witnesses by whom the district attorney is
eoing to prove that Lizzie Borden actually
did buy poison.
 </text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1893-06-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=murder+trial+Borden+Lizzie+BORDEN+LIZZIE</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>MISS RUSSELL AND THE BURNT
DRESS.
Mrs. Churchill's examination was fin
ished at 11.20. A fivo-minute recess fol
lowed, during which the prisoner talked
with Charles J .Holmes, of Fall River.
Alice Russell was called at H.tO.
Mis Russell deserted Lizzie's burning
of the dress the Sunday after the mur
der. First saw Lizzie In the kitchen
with the dress, nnd Lizzie said: "I am
going to burn up this old thing covered
with paint."
Witness went out and came In again
and saw Lizzie standing near the cup
board door and tearing or ripping small
portion of dress. A skirt was lying
on the shelf.
Witness said: "I would not let anybody
see you do that," to which Lizzie said
nothing, but moved back one step
toward tho cupboard door.
Afterwards witness said: "I am afraid
the worst thing you could have done
was to burn that dress."
Lizzie replied: "Oh, why did you let
mo do It? Why did not you tell me?"
The dress was a cheap, light-blue cot
ton bedford cord, with small dark fig
ure, with witness had once noticed Liz
zie wearing in the Spring, when new.
Ex-Gov. Robinson's cross-examination
failed to shake Miss Russell's direct
testimony.
On re-dtrect she testified, against ob
jection, by defense, that Bedford Is a
cheap dress material, and that the cup
board In which witness saw a part of
the dress at the time of the burning was
used only for kitchen utensils.
At 12.50' John Cunningham testified
about the murder. Court then took a
recess from 1 to 2.15.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1893-06-17/ed-1/?sp=1&q=trial+Emma+Borden+Lizzie</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>THE DEFENSE RESTS.
All the Testimony in Favor
of Lizzie Borden Now
In.
Her Sister Emma Appears in
Behalf of the Accused
Womanr
Breach Between Lizzie and
Her Stepmother Had Been
Healed.
Only One Witness, a Boy, Now
Remains to Be Exam
ined.
Nptw Bedfokd. Mass-, June 16.—
There was less of a crowd at the court
house this morning at the resumption of
the Borden trial than at any time since
the beginning of the trial. The decision
relative to the admission of the evidence
of the Portuguese who saw the man
with the bloody hatchet was in order
the first thing this morning, and after
the jury had been polled counsel en
tered into a consultation with the jus
tices upon some points which the latter
desired to hear. Following this
the court said it was clear that tha evi
dence offered on the head above referred
to could not be admitted. Mrs. Mary R.
Holmes, a neighbor and member of the
church which Miss Borden attended,
was then called to the stand. Witness
was asked whether Lizzie went down
to look at her father's body before the
funeral, was objected to, but the
court, assuming the question to be
preliminary, allowed it to be answered,
witness answering in tho affirmative.
Witness was asked what Lizzie did
when she went down into the room, and
this was objected to; thereupon the
chief just ice called counsel to the desk
for consultation, the result of which
was thai the question was changed
to "At this time when she was viewing
her father did she shed tears?" The
answer was yea. Miss Emma Borden
was called. Sue 'estitied as follows:
Einma'H Testimony.
"We have lived in the house we now
live in for twenty-one years last May.
At the time of the murder. Lizzie was
possessed of property as follows: $170
in the B. M. C. Safe Deposit and Trust
company, $2,000 in the Massasoit Na
tional bank, $500 in the Union Savings
bank, 8141 in the Fail River Five Cents
Savings bank, two shares of
the Fall River National bank
btock. four shares of the Mer
chants' Manufacturing company stock,
five shares of the same another date.
My father wore a ring on his finger.
It was given him by Lizzie. She had
worn it herself before, and he constant
ly won; It after, and it was buried with
him, I have made an inventory of the
clothes in the closet on the afternoon it
was searched. I was there when the
seatoh was goiug on."
Witness was asked what Dr. Dolan
said in regard to a thorough search.
"The doctor said the search had been
as thorough as it could be unless the
paper was torn from the walls or the
carpet taken up. The Bedford cord
dress was made the first week in May at
our homo; it was a very cheap
dress, 12ja or 15 cents a yard, and about
eight or nine yards in it, ulainly
trimmed; not more than two days were
used in making tho dress; Lizzie and I
assisted, as we always did. The paint
ers began work after the dress was
made. Lizzie got some
Paint on This Drese
within two weeks after It was made.
She got the paint on the front breadth
and on the side. The dress was hanging
in the front closet on the day 1 came
home. 1 know, because I went in to
hang up a dress and found there was no
nail."
Q; Did you say anything to Lizzie
about that dress because tnere was no
nail there?
A- ldid; I said "You haven't de
stroyed that old dress yet; why don't
you do so?" It was very dirty, badly
faded, and I don't remember having
seen her use it for some time. It
couldn't have been made over be
cause, besides being badly soiled,
the material and color was
such as to render it impossible.
The next 1 saw of the Bedford dress I
was in the kitchen Saturday when 1
heard my sister's voice; 1 looked around
and saw her with the dress on her arm.
She said, "I'm going to burn this old
dress;" and 1 said: "I would," or
"Why don't you?" and turned ajvay.
I did not see her bum the
dress. Miss Uussell was there at
the time she told Mr. llanscom a false
hood, atid I asked her what that was
for. She said he asked her if all the
dresses were in the house that were
there at the time of the murder, and
she had said yes. Then it was decided
between us all that she go and tell Mr.
lianscom she
Had Told a Falsehood.
My sister said at the time: "Why
didn't you tell him about it? Why did
you let me do it?" 1 remember the
story about the quarrel between my
sister and I. I never had any such
conversation with my sister as was
reported; there was never any
trouble or quarrel in the matron's
nufitQ between us while she was
tl:ere, or anything that could be con
strued into a quarrel: Lizzie never did
put up her hngcr and say anything
about giving in. Witness contended
that the relations between Lizzie and
Mrs. Borden were entirely cordial.
Witness said that the breach caused by
the giving of the property to her mother
was never healed, so far as she was
concerned, although it was on Lizzie's
part. She knew of no enemy her step
mother had in the world.
The dressmaker who made the famous
paint stained dress next swore that
Lizzie could not have worn the pink
wrapper over it to conceal blood spots,
had tiiere been any. Said the witness,
"The skirt was longer by half a linirer
tl^ui she had been in the habit of wear
ing. It was a cheap cotton dress. The
painters were painting the house
when Lizzie was wearing the dress
she put it on as soon as it was done, i
sr,\v the dress after it was painted. The
!';iiu: Was in Front and Back.
She Jiad on an old wrapper whicli
this was to take the place of; she cut
some pieces wit of the old wrapper
while I was" tuere and touk it down
stairs.
Phoebe B. M. Bowen, wife of Dr.
Bowen, was the next witness. She was
cailed f into the house right sifter the
Storm was given, and found Mrs.
Churchill was fanning -Lizzie. She
thought Lizzie had tainted. Her lips
a.id eliin were quivering. She was
flaked about the blue "that had
been in evidence all aicrj*-.'. "1 should
say it was the waist," she said. She
was not sure about the skirt. District
Attorney Knowlton wanted to know
how Lizzie's hands were. They were
white and perfectly clean.
Mrs. Hinguatn was recalled. She was
asked if she had made any experiment
to learn If a person on the floor of the
room in which Mrs. Borden was found
could be seen from the hallway. Johu
V. Morse lay on the floor, between the
bed and the dressing case. The bed was
three feet from the bureau. Could you
see him ou the floor?
"I stood in the hall and a person of
my height could not see him ou the
floor."
Mrs. Bingahm is about as tall as
Lizzie. Miss Annie M. White, the of
ficial stenographer in the court at Fall
River, testified that certain tilings had
been testiiied to at the first hearing. It
was just 3:15 when ex.Gov. Kobinson
said:
"The Defense Rest*."
Mr. Moody asked for fifteen minutes
in which to prepace the rebuttal, which
the court eranted. At 3:45 the jury re
turned to the court room. Marshall
Billiard was the first witness called in
rebuttal. He wa3 asked as to the quar
rel in the matron's room. He said:
"I saw Mrs. Reatran about it. Mrs.
Reagan and Rev. Buck entered the of
fice. She handed me the paper and said
she was willing to sign it. 1 said to her:
'If you do so, do so in direct violation of
my orders.' 1 told her if she had any
thing to say she had better say it in
court."
That was Ml, and then Policeman
Mullaly, the one who testified that the
missing handle of the hatchet had been
found, was asked if he had received
any information from Hyrnan Rubruski.
He said he had. That ended'the defense
for today, and all of it. In fact, except
that of a boy in Fall River who on Mon
day morning will testify regarding the
two boys, Brown and Barlow, who were
on the stand yesterday.
The court and couusel held a consul
tation. At iiSNConclusion Justice Mason
addressed the jury, telling them not to
form an opinion until they had heard
the whole ease. Then au adjournment
was had until Monday.
The boys Brown and Barlow were
outside the court house this afternoon
complaining bitterly of thu treatment
that Barlow was subjected to last night
by members of the Fall River police
force. When the boys had testified yes
terday, so they say, they were locked in
a room in the court house, and there
Detective Shaw tried to find out how
they came to appear as wituesses, and
then, as they allege, he tried to intimi
date them.</text>
    </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1893-06-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=murder+trial+Borden+Lizzie</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>"If Lizzie killed her mother at 0:45 did
she come down and greet her father in that
bloc stained drcsst I would not bo sur
prised If they said she did this slaughtering
while nude. She did not try to got Bridget
out of the house. Don't you think she would
have sent her out on some errand
The claw-headed hatchet was then taken
up by 1 the lawyer. Ho pointed out that Dr.
Dolan and the other doctors disagreed as to
what had been used to kill the Bordcns.
The handlelnss hatchet was referred to. Ex-
Governor Koblnson maintained that the
blade of the hatchet could not cut its way
cleanly through Mr Bordon's eye balls nor
could it have made n cut in Mrs. Borden's
hair as if it had boon made with a pair of
shears. The hair found on the claw-headed
hatchet which thc'irovernment had at first
called dog hair was cow hair.
"If those are not the implements with
which the murder \yas committed where is
itt Fall Hiver appears to bo prolific in the
way of hatchets.
Miss Ilorilon'o Actions.
During the latter part of the summing-up
in her favor Miss'Borden removed her fan
from her face leaned forward and looked
steadily at the jury1. She held her hands
somewhat to the Tight and waved her fan
gently. She nover-ffiniled when the govern
ment told what tho'lato Benjamin F. Butler
had said of the case. It was "Why docs
not Dr. Dolan hold cm autopsy on Lizzie Borden
den and find theihatehctt"
"Tho excluslVo opportunlty theory the
lawyer said later"was simply an anticipa
tion which was notreallzod. The side screen
door was unfadtenfcd from 0 o'clock that
morning until 11:151 The back screen door
was open. A person could got into the house
by simply avoiding- Bridget on .tho outside
and j izzio on the inside. A man could have
gene to the house for the tjurpose of killing
Mr. Borden /liid happatnhg to meet Mrs.

Bordeu. proba'bly some one she knew struck
her down. Then ho waited for uorden
to come homo and killed him. It
would have been the most natural thing in
the world for the assassin to have left the
door of the spare room open. Then as to
the young man who was seen outside. What
was ho but the outside spy for the one com
mitting the deed. The Job was not done by
one man alone.
At this point a recess was taken. Mr.
Kobmson had talked half nn hour longer
than the time which had been allotted to
him and had not yet finished. What ho
said and the way ho said it disappointed
his friends very much.</text>
    </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1893-06-21/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Borden+Lizzie+guilty+trial</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>FREE FROM QUILT.
Lizzie Borden Acquitted
by the Jury.
WHO COMMITTED THE DEED.
Though She Is Net the Culprit, Vet
Is the Mystery No Nearer
.solution.
'1 two versions of the story of the horn
ing of the defendant's dress were irrecon
cilable. He iii-cu .-cd the defendant's con
duct since the order, and eald the pro
duct on of ti.e hatchet was no part of the
Government's ease, and closed with an
eloquent appeal to the jury.
'J lie court then took a recess, and on re
assembling defendant was given an op
portunity to sneak. She said: "I am in
nocent, but I will leavs my case in your
bands and with my counsel."
Justice Dewey then 'barged the jury.
He. defined the different degrees of murder
and stated tbat the resumption of Inno
cence was increased by the defendant's
character. There must be a real and
operative motive for a crime of this sort.
The Judge further charged the jury to
weigh the evidence to see whether the de
fendant's permanent state of mmd showed
a motive for tbe crimes. Every material
allegation in the indictment must be
proved beyond a reasonable doubt, that is
to a moral certainty. He compared direct
and circumstantial evidence and said that
the failure, to prove an essential fact would
be fatal, but the failure to prove a helpful
circumstance not a fact might not be.
Lizzie's statements about the note were
discussed at length, and the Judge 'said
they must be satisfied that they were false.
Every fact proved must be reasonably
consistent with guilt. The Government
dii not show that anybody else bad an op
portunity to commit the crime, but it most
prove the defendant committed It. The
jury must reason as to the effect of de
fendant's conduct and statements. They
were not to reach a conclusion from expert
testimony, but were lo apply to ita reason
able judgment. They might convict, even
if satisfied that the act was done by an
other party, if they also found that de
fendant was present aiding and abetting
the commission of the crime. The mere
fact that defendant did not testify should
not influence them against her. X;->
Judge Dewey, continuing, said that the
government claims that these acts come
under the head of murder in the first de
gree. The law says that in order to prove
Ibis every claim must be established be
yond a reasonable doubt. It is stated that
the government presents its case on cir
cumstantial evidence. It is understood by
the couil that the governmeritelaimed that
the essential fact embraced in the note
matter, namely, that she made statements
which she knew to be false when she was
making them, but contemplates the possi
bility of there being an assassin. Might he
not have come upon her when the note
was at liana and removed it as one of the
links In the evidence? lv cases of circum
stantial evidence, unless every link holds
good, the chain is worthless. The jury is
asked to bear in mind the supposed fact
that there is nothing to connect the de
fendant with tbe murder as far as outward
appearances go.
At the conclusion of the charge the at
torneys consulted a lew moments and then
tbe jury was allowed to retire.
It was just 4:30 o'clock when the specta
tors, who bad kept their seats patiently
during the retirement of the jury, noticed
a movement indicating their return. A
moment later the twelve men filed into
their seats and were polled. Miss Borden
was asked to stand up and the foreman
was asked to return the verdict, which he
announced as "not guilty."
Then all the dignity and decorum of the
courtroom vanished. A cheer went up
which might have been beard a mile away</text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1893-06-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Acquitted+Borden+Lizzie</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>NOT GUILTY.
Acquitted of tho Horrible
Double Butchery.
The Verdict Arrived at Yesterday
Afternoon After a Vory Brief
Deliberation.
Nkw Redford, Moes., June 20. As
sociated Press. Governor Robinson
tuis ttfternooD rehearsed chronological
events connected with tho Borden mur
der. There is no doubt in the evidence
against Mies Borden, he said. The evi
dence Bhows the defendant did not
know whero the alleged weapon was
kept. Lizzie Borden was at Inmo on
tlio morning the murders were com
mitted, and if she had geno upstairs
and looked under tho bed sho might
have seen the body of her step-mother.
Bridget Sullivan, who for two years had
hr-pn n.ser to tho family than anyone
else, never heard a quarrel between
Lizzie nnd Mre. Borden.
Tho speaker then related th fact of
the alleged blood-stained dress and tho
burning of it. "If," said he, "Lizzie
Borden killed her step-mother at 9:45,
did she come down and greet her father
in tho blood-stained dress? She must
Iiavo changed clothing and changed
again after tho second slaughter. Liz
ziu did not try to get Bridget o.tit of the
house. Don't you think sho would have
sent heron some errands'.'"
"The attorney pointed out that the
doctors disagreed as to what had been
ueed to kill the Borden's and touched
upon tho clawheaded hatchet and
thu hatchet without a handle. "It
these were not tho implements with
which the murder was committed,
where are they?" he inquired.
"Anybody," continued Governor Kob
inson, "could have gotten into the
houee by simply avoiding Bridget on
the outside and Lizzie on 1he inside."
The lawyer field that tho young man
Feen in the vicinity was an outside spy
for the person committing the deed,
that the job bad not been done by ono
person. At 3 o'clock, when the gover
nor closed, District Attorney Knowlton
began to sum up for the prosecution.
He addressed himself to the motive
for the mnrder; pointed the enmity of
Lizzie toward her stepmother as suffi
cient motive for her murder, and said
ker killing necessitated the killing of
her father. Stern was the man who
knew of the enmity nnd loved the dead
wifo.
The only way for Lizzie to possfblr
escape punishment, he raid, lav in the
killing of her father. This theory was
the onlv one which would consistently
account for tho double murder, taking
place within a period of an hour and
half between the acts.
With this the prosecution closed.
Justice Dewey then charged the jury,
which, after a brief deliberation, re
turned a verdict of not guilty.
</text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028490/1893-06-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Borden+Lizzie+trial+guilty</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>SPECTATORS GO WILD.
Great Joy Over the Acquittal of
Lizzie Borden.
HO ATTEMPT TO STOP THE 1T0ISE.
TU Sheriff's Eyes l'lllcd Witt Tears,
"Whllo Iho ftntrly Judges Staled nt t!(0
lUro Wnlls Tlio Defendant llrcftlti
Down Over tlio Strain.
New Bedmhid, Mass., Juno 31. Tho
'closing scones in tlio trial of Lizzio 33or
den, whon tho verdict of 'Not guilty"
was announced by Uio foronmn of tho
jury, wns in dircot contrast with thoso
which had preceded it. llorotoforo nil
hud been decorous and in koopittg with
tho dignity of tho most dignlllod court
in tho country, hut when tlio vtrdiet of
'Not guilty" waa returned a cheer wont
MISS LIZZIK BORDEN.
tup which might hnvo boen heard half a
mile away through tlve opon windows,
tond thoro was uo attempt mado ta
check it.</text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1892-08-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=murder+Fall+River+Borden+Andrew</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>THfclR MURDERER STOLE IN.
j A nidi MAN AND II IB WIFE KILLED
BTEALTIIILY AT HOME.
i
Millionaire, Aadrew J. Berden or Fait Illver
Hal Jnet Returned from the Bnnk and
"ITaa Lying; oa Lounge la HI Sitting
iBoam When aa Aesaasln mipned In aad
ntraeh lllnirllhw Am or CITip-Hr,
Ilnrdfa Was Up Hlalrt and Was Mur
dered hy the Rum. Inatraaseat The Bad.
It Slacevered hr a Ilatithter 'Who Ilnd
Dnh Out oflao llonao Only a Few Mln.
atee-The Servant Vg. Blalra neard No
NoUe-AII Annuel of Kecape Covered,
lint NoTrnce of the Murderer Secured.
FaLtllrvEn, Aug. 4. Andrew J. Borden, the
millionaire mill owner, nnd hi teed wlfo were
murdered In their homo to-day Just before
coca, and although thore were othor members
of the family on the premiiei at the time, they
beard no sonnd, and the murderer eicaped
without leaving a clue, so far as Is known, al
though his clothing must hare been covered
With the blood of his victims. The boldness
of the crime and tho utter absence of anr ap
parent motive make It the more myttorlous.
No attempt at robbery bad boon made. Who
the murderer was. why he committed the
ortme, or where he went to, are the questions
Which the police would like to solve, but thus
far they have found nothing that can help
them. They have arrested three persons on
suspicion, but the only suspicious circum-
Stanoe albout them was the fact that they
Iwert teen in tlfe neighborhooiabout the hear
Of the murder</text>
    </result>

    </results> 
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chinese-exclusion-act</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053040/1882-05-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Bill+bill+Chinese+signed&r=-0.835,-0.023,2.671,1.107,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Chinese Bill.
The bill signed by the President on the
8th inst., entitled "An act to execute cer
tain treutv stipulations relating to Chinese,"
provides In the first section for the suspen
sion of the immigration of Chinese laborers
to the United States for a period of ten
years, counting from the expiration of
ninety days after the passage of the act,
that is for to years from the 30th dav of
July 1882. The second section provides
lor" tiie punishment of masters of vessels
who shall land in the U. S-, Chinese labor
ers in violation of section first, bv u fine of
$500 for each immigrant and imprisonment
not exceeding one year. Section third pro
vides tor certificates of identity tor Chinese
laborers now in the country, who may
wish to visit China and return. Section
twelve makes it the duty of the President
of tiie United States to cause to be removed
to tiie place from whence they came, and
at the cost of the United States every Chi
nese person who shall have unlawfully en
tered this country by land or water, after
being brought before some justice, judge or
commissioner of a court of tiie United
States. Section thirteen exempts diplo
matic and other officers of tin; Chinese
Government and their body and .musehold
servants from the provisions of the act.
The two following sections are the ones
against which so much opposition lias been
shown by Republican Congressmen.
Section' 14. That hereafter no State
court or court of the United States shall ad
mit Chinese to citizenship; and all laws in
conflict with this act are repealed.
Section- 15. That tiie words "Chinese
Laborei s" wherever used in this act shall
be constructed to mean both skilled and un
skilled laborers and Chinese employ ed in
mining</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040052/1899-09-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=coolie+coolies&r=-0.537,0.192,1.858,0.77,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>An Unfair Competition.
From Orange Judd Farmer.
The alien contract labor law is- being griev
ously violated in Hawaii. No specific form of
government having been provided by congress
lor the Sandwich Islands, the Dole regime con
tinues in power. It is notoriously controlled
bv the sugar planters, who are developing their
plantations on a most extraordinary scale by
the use of artificial irrigation and Japanese and
Chinese coolie labor. Nearly $20,000,000 has
been invested in plantation improvements there
since annexation, and more than 12,000 coolies
have been imported during the past few
mouths. These Asiatic coolies, who are vir
tually slaves, now ontnuinbei the rest of the
population, both native and foreign.</text>
      </result>
  <result>
    <id>https://loc.gov/resource/sn85042448/1892-04-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+Act+Chinese+exclusion+Exclusion&r=0.627,0.341,0.434,0.18,0</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>A CELESTIAL HORDE.
Hiding in Sepestere! Noois, Reafly
for the Break.
ONLY ONE MORE RIVER TO CROSS.
Should the Chinese Exclusion Act Only
Expire Tuesday Night.
THE AliCREOATIOS 8PKEA11 ITSELF
A Possible Show for the Agents of the
Government to Get in and do
Likewise.
Detroit, April 29. The woods are
full of-Chinese over in Canada. It is
said tbe denizens of the Flowery King
dom, in large numbers, are' dodging be
hind trees and hiding in sequestered
nooks, ready to make a break for the
United States the minute the clock
strikes 12 on the night of 3d. They
all firmly believe that on May 4th the
Chinese exclusion act will expire, and
they hope to slip into tbe United States
before the law now under consideration,
in congress can be put into effect. This
numerous aggregation has consequently
spread itself out along the border all the
way from here to Vancouver, and is only
biding its time to get into this great
republic. Detroit, however, seems to be
the most favorable point at which the
Celestials can cross the border, for it is
the city most adjacent to Chicago,
whither nearly all of them seem to be
bound. Because of this fact, Detroit has
always been a favorite port at which to
land after the trip through Canada from
the Pacific, and, although there are no
statistic to prove it, it is undisputed
that more Chinese have been smuggled 4
across the Detroit river,, at various
points, than at any other place in the
country. Capt. Pratt, special treasury
agent, says the Chinese are avoiding
Windsor, because they know they will
be closely watched there. The border is
as closely guarded as it can be by the
small force stationed here. There is
more chance of the Chinese trying to
cross Marine city, or the month of the,,
river, than at Detroit.</text>
    </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-26/ed-1/?sp=12&q=act+Chinese+exclusion&r=-0.054,0.226,0.834,0.346,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>According to the Chinese circular issued
last January Tarpey and his friends in
tended to bring from China to Mexico
more than 1.000,000 coolies. Just- how
many were to remati- in Mexico Tarpey
did not state.
 First— Th« fisherman must get i for v himself
T. tea, rice, i vegetables, clothing and goods from
the. foreman or Chinese merchants. The Pacific
Charter Company -is not after that r kind or
business.
•A Second— These necessaries will •be carried by
the i company. The freight charges will be
cheap.;- Other than the fishermen and mer
.chants will have -to pay higher.
:i..v Third— When 1 the fishermen begin work they
must -make a contract with foremen to buy
:_¦¦ their implements t from Chinese merchants. If
-not, the contract lls broken.
Fourth— The Chinese merchants must buy the
salt or dried fish, besides canned fish or other
wise the foremen will take charge. Acapulco
and all other stopping places for the ships will
have warehouses. Canneries will be established
all along the coast and the company will have
a small steamer to visit the canneries every
week to take.-the dried and salt fish to Aca
pulco.
</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/46032385/1901-12-06/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+Chinese+exclusion&r=-0.541,0.111,2.082,0.863,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Yellow Peril.
It will be necessary for the present congress
to. take acjtion upon the Chinese exclusion act
which expires by limitation May 24, 1902. The
Kjansas City platform contained the following
plank on the subject:
We favor the continuance and strict en-
forcement of the Chinese exclusion law and
its application to the samo classes of all
'Asiatic races.
This plank was unanimously agreed upon by
the platform committee, and there was no dissent
from it among the delegates. It is to be expected,
therefore, that the proposition to extend the
Chinese exclusion act will receive the support of
all the democrats in the house and senate. The
editor of The Commoner received a letter a few
days ago from a democrat who complained that
the laboring men of the Pacific slope had ignored
the. Chinese question in the last campaign and
suggested that it would only be a merited punish
ment if the republican party refused to extend the
exclusion act. It is not unnatural that some
resentment should be felt toward those who sup
ported the republican party in spite of the dangers
which republican supremacy involves, and yet no
one can justify himself in either supporting a bad
policy or in failing to protest against it merely be
cause the policy would punish .some who ought to
have exerted themselves to prevent ij:. That
many of the republican leaders are in favor of a
..policy, Jfcat will flood the country with cheap
Chinese labor, is true, and that an imperial policy
tends to lend encouragement to the cheap labor
proposition, is also true, but the failure of the
laboring men' to see these dangers in advance
would not justify .democrats in remaining quiet
on this subject, although the republicans are in
"power and are responsible for legislation.
The Chinese question is one that effects the en
tire country, not the Pacific Coast alone or the
laboring men alone.</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-04-17/ed-1/?sp=1&q=CHINESE+Chinese+exclusion+EXCLUSION&r=0.106,0.727,1.009,0.418,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Patterson also defended the section In
the Mitchell bill excluding Chinese from
American ships,' declaring that it is es
sential to the protection of American la
bor "on the sea. The opposition to this
provision meant, he said, that it was in
tended to subsidize the ships and then
allow ;their owners to go into the cheap
est markets to secure labor, leaving the
American seamen to their fate. The ef
fect would be -to drive American sailors
from the American ships, which would be
contrary to the policy of the American
people, who want American ships under
the American flag and manned by Ameri
can sailors. As- for the flag, it was a
mere piece of cloth, its only significance
being attached. to what it stood for. If it
was .to be raised at the masthead of
ships manned by yellow skins and white
livered "men, the representative* of a
that amendment fails to prohibit the Chi
nese from going into the" Philippines.
Whatever the motive of Senators in this
omission, he said, he was quite sure that r
those outside the Seriate who were op
posing the pending, bill have a .well-de
fined and clearly-determined policy, and
that* that policy la to leave the Philip
pines-in such a condition that those
islands shall be cultivated by the aid of
Chinese labor, no matter what the result
to the real inhabitants of the islands or
to the honor of the United States. He
quoted with approbation the report of
General McArthur, and said that tho pro
posed legislation is equivalent to a notice
that the policy of exclusion is looked
upon'wlth disfavor and he could not con
ceive a more indefensible act than during
the formative period In the Philippines to
flood that country with a people whom
the natives hate and who. they believe,
would drive them from their land and
its-trade and commerce.
Patterson spoke with especial y reference
to^thc. Platt amendment, calling attention
to the fact that as at present constituted
POINTS BY PATTERSON.
When- Turner, concluded. Quay of Penn
sylvania asked how. much time he would
be allowed in speaking upon an amend
ment he wrbuld /offer for the admission
of Christianized Chinamen. He -said he
did not" desire to make a speech in the
usual' acceptance of "the- term, ,"as .that
practice,"- he sald,'"I am content to leave
to "the senior wranglers of Senate,'be
ing entirely satisfied to sit" at; their f feet
while they" explain th© mysteries of legis
lation.',' He added that he desired to
have read some printed extracts bearing
upon^the conduct of these; converted ''Chi-,
nese during, the! Boxer uprising. He was
assured^that he would be heard.
Turner .then entered upon a discussion
of the -merits of the. Chinese »exclusion
bill.,' He spoke of .the Chinese, declaring
that\twQ-facedness ;is. a characteristic of
that people,', from which not even the
Emperor is free. He: also declared .that
the great Chinese Viceroy who had re
cently died \_had';. amassed his Vcoiossal
fortune by the corrupt use of office, and
followed this i remark with the statement
that! if Chinese were to be admitted to
the United States upon -the certificates
of' Chinese^ officials; there .might.be .no
pretenseof a check upon.lt."</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1905-06-30/ed-1/?sp=4&q=ACT+act+Chinese+CHINESE+exclusion+EXCLUSION&r=-0.287,0.614,1.097,0.455,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE CHINESE
EXCLUSION ACT.
One of the big questions which is
agitating thit country at tho present
time is the Chinese exclusion act, and
the effect its rigid enforcement has
now and may have in the future, on
American commerce and trade in
China. The exportation of cotton and
cotton goods to China has grov-n from
almost nothing to $40,000,000 in a few
yca-s. Other lines of exports to the
celestial kingdom have shown very
large gams. The American manufac
turer is clamoring tor an open door
to the trade of China. The American
manufacturer has always been solf-
ifsh and in most instances, been ready
to sacrifice the good of the people to
his own profit and selfish ends. It
matters little to the manufacturer of
cotton goods in New England or the
south if the Pacific coast and adja
cent territory is overrun with cheap
Chinese coolies, the lowest strata of
Chinese life. 5f he can find a ready
and a profitable market for a few
more millions of dollars of cotton
goods and other products of his shops.
7"he cry for more liberal immigration
Jiws for the Chinese comes wholly
Irom the manufacturers. Tne people
of the Pacific coast don't want the
aan at any price. He is a men-
ace to this country and his very pres
ence exerts a contaminating in
fluence. It is impossible for him to
amalgamate with the people of this
country. He can not become a citizen
and ho has no desire to make this
land of the free his home and reside
here permanently. Personally he Is
as objectionable as tho negro of the
J south and if we must have cheap labor
1 let us give the negro a chance. "We
lave him with us and while he is not
.as skillful as the Chinaman or as In
dustrious, he Is by far the best cheap
laborer in the world.
The Chinese exclusion act has been
in operation for more than twenty
years. At tho time of its passage a
perfect horde of orientals were
streaming Into this country, over
running the Pacific coast states, and
drifting far back into the interior. The
exclusion act stopped this unholy in
vasion at once and the flow of China
men began to go the other way. There
were at that time more than a quar
ter of a million Chinamen In the
"United States. During these twenty
years this number has been on the
gradual decline. Death has thinned
tho ranks of the yellow skinned sons
of the east and a large proportion of
the Chinamen who were in this coun
try have made their "stake" and re
turned to China to remain. In San
Francisco. Los Angeles, Portland and
Seattle the gradual decrease in the
number of Chinese has been most
notable. It is doubtful if at the pros
sent time there are 50,000 Chinese in
the entire country, and the country
will be infinitely better off when
these, too, "have folded their tents,
like the Arab, and silently stolen
away."
The manufacturers, for years, have
kept an outrageous tariff on all
classes of manufactured goods by
their cry of "protection to American
labor," and they have filtched mill
ions of dollars from the pockets of
the people under the guise of a tariff
to enrich their own. It matters not
to them how heavy the burden on
the shoulders of the people, just so
they get their pound of flesh. Now
they wo ild throw wide open the doors
to the Chinese in order to get a few
more dollars of trade.
We very much mistake the fcentl-
ment of the American people if they
cater to such a cry or agree to admit
the Chinaman on any terms. Let the
door remain closed and barred to the
celestials of the east forever and if
more stringent regulations were
adopted In regard to immigrants from
other countries it would be better
and not worse for the country.</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1906-01-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+Chinese+exclusion</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EXCLUSION LAW IS VALID
COURT OF APPEALS DECLARES
CONGRESS HAD POWER TO
EXTEND STATUTE.
Cincinnati, Jan. 10.The case of
Hong Wing against the United States,
involving the Chinese exclusion act,
was decided in favor of the United
States circuit court of appeals in this
city, the court holding that the act of
.April 7, 1904, continued the exclusion
act in full force, congress haying full
potyer to dp so.
Hong Wing is one of six Chinamen
who had been ordered deported under
the provisions of the Chinese exclu
sion act and the cases being identical
the one decision will apply to all six.
Attorneys for the applicant main
tained that the exclusion act was void
and that their clients eould not be de
ported.
The decision was announced by
Judge Richards, who said that the
main point presented to the court was
whether the act of April 7, 1904, con
tinued the Chinese exclusion act in
force and the court was satisfied that
it did do so without reference to any
existing treaties or regulations. The
act was passed in view of the treaty
expiring and it had continued the pro
visions of the treaty. Congress has
the power to modify, reject or concur
in treaties and it had done what was
wholly within its power in passing this
act. The decision of the lower court
was, therefore, sustained and the ap
peal dismissed. '-..hffam</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1907-10-24/ed-1/?sp=5&q=act+Chinese+exclusion</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LET CHINESE COME.
Seth Low Says Only the Coolie Class
Should Be Excluded.
Chicago. Oct. 24. Immigration,
with special reference to the Chinese
exclusion act, was discussed by former
Mayor Seth Low of New York in an
address before the Chicago association
of commerce.
Mr. Low indorsed the socalled
"Roosevelt policy" of excluding from
this country only the class of Chinese
known as "Coolies."
"I am In favor of the purpose, but
not the form of the Chinese exclusion
act." said Mr. Low. "President Roofie
velt is right in his policy of opposition
to the slavelike labor of coolies in this
free country.
"It is an insult to an old, wise and
proud race such as the Chinese to ex
clude their students and great men
from our shores. I am in sympathy
with the great object of the Chinese
exclusion act to keep the Pacific
coast free from the numerical prepon
derance of an Asiatic population. If
there ever was a matter of publib
policy In which the 'undesirable citi
zen' doctrine should be enforced to the.
limit it Is the immigration question.
"Degenerates and people low
morals are the most undesirable class
es of immigrants. But there should
be no educational tests. Physical fibei
and stamina should be the chief quali
ties required."</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1909-03-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Act+Chinese+Exclusion</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-dollar-princesses</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026844/1874-08-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jerome+Jennie+Churchill+Marriage+Settlement+Marquis+Blandford</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW YOHK C1TI.
A MABBIAOB 6BTTI.KMRNT.
Nkw Yobk, August 12.?Among the
papers recorded at tho Registers office
yesterday was a settlement mado by
Leonard VV. Jerome and wife in view of
tho contemplated marriage ol their
daughter Jennie with Lord Kandolph
Henry Bpencer Churchill, son of the English
Marquis of Blandford. Under this
marriage settlement Thos. M. Foote, of
this city, and George Charles Spencer
Churchill, Marquis ot Blandford, aro constituted
truatees to receive and pay over
an annuity of $10,000 gold, and It is a
stipulated case that Lady Churchill, Miss
Jerome, should die belore ber husband,
leaving no issue of her surviving, that
$125,000 in gold shall threafter be paid to
Lord Churchill, and further provision is
made for the payment of $250,000 in gold
to their heirs should both of them die
leaving no issue of their marriage. Tho
Union League Clnb House is made security
for this settlement</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1895-09-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Consuelo+Vanderbilt+Marlborough+Duke+Landed</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SHE HAS LANDED HER DUKE
Consuelo Vanderbilt Will Wed
Marlborough
ENGAGEMENT IS ANNOUNCED
The Duke Himself Is Authority for Statement
Vanderbllts VI 111 Now Be Connected With the
Principal Ducal Families o»
England
Assoclated Press Special Wire.
NEW YORK, Sept. 20.—The engage
ment of the youne duke of Marlborough
to Miss Consuelo Vanderbilt, daughter ofa
Mr. and Mrs. W. K. Vanderbilt, which
bas been repeatedly affirmed and denied
during the past month, was formally an
nounced tonight.
The duke himself is authority for tbe
statement. Ho was seen at tbe Waldorf
hotel aud asked concerning the truth of
THE TWO TRADERS
THE DUKE OF fTARLBOROUGH, Who Has Traded His Title for /Irs.
Vanderbilt's Millions
tho current reports, whereupnn be re
quested that the facts be made public in
tbe following words:
"It is otliciaily announced that a mar
riage lias been arranged between the
duke of Marlborough and Miss Consuelo
Vanderbilt. The engagement wis ar
ranged by Mrs. VanderbiltV friends and
those of the duke of Marlborough. Tbe
wedding will take place toward the latter
part of this year in New York."
The duke said he would leave tomor
iow on a trip through the state as tbe
guest ot Sir Rivers Wilson, president of
the Grand Trunk. This marriage will
connect the house of Vanderbilts to the
principal ducal families ot tlie British
empire, particularly those of Burcleugh
ltoxbury and Abercorn. The duke of
Abercorn is aii uncle ot tbe duke of Marl
borough.</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1903-11-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Duke+Roxburghe+Heiress+Bride+Goelet</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE DUKE OF ROXBURGHE
GETS HIS HEIRESS-BRIDE
(ASSOCIATED PRESS CABLEGRAM
NEW YORK, Nov. 11 The wedding of the Duke of Roxburghe
and Miss May Goelet was a gorgeous ceremony. The police had
difficulty in restraining the mob of women who surrounded the
carriage to see the bride.Miss May Goelet, the most courted
girl in the world and the richest girl in
her own right in America, will hence
forth be known as the Duchess of Rox
burghe. The Duchess is worth in her
own right about $30,000,000.
It is eight years since the courting of
Miss Goelet began. In that time the
twenty men who have been most
conspicuous among her suitors have all
had interesting or remarkable adven
tures. Some have gone to war, some
have died, some have become famous.
The twenty were: The Duke of Rox
burghe, the Grand Duke Boris of Rus
sia, Prince Franc-i of Teck, the Prince
Henri of Orleans. Prince Hugo of Ho
henlohe, the Prince of Sagan, the Duke
of Abruzzi, the Duke of Manchester,
the Earl of Shaftesbury, Lord Ingestre,
Lord Dalmeny, the Hon. Lionel Roths
child, Captain Oswald Ames. Henry
Cavendish, Lord Crichton, Paul Des
chanel, Santos Dumont, Signor Marco
ni, Jasques Lebaudy and Craig Wads
worth. Among them they possessed $81,000,
000, this sum being divided among
twelve of them, while the rest were
virtually penniless. These twelve had
fourteen splendid castles, palaces and
villas in England, France and Ger
many. Eight years ago when this universal
international courtship began Miss
Goelet was only seventeen years old.
But with social talents and cleverness
inherited from a mother of the noted
R. T. Wilson family, and a perfect
education, she took a leading place in
society at once. The occasion on
which she first attracted the attention
of American society was at the wed
ding of Miss ("onsuelo Vanderbilt to the
Duke of Marlborough in 1S95, when she
was a bridesmaid.
The new Duchess is slight, dark and
very attractive. It is an exaggeration
to say that she is strikingly handsome,
as many have done. Two cynical so
ciety men were discussing the point,
and one of them said:
"Would you call her face handsome?"
"Not exactly but her fortune Is,"
said the other.
Today at twenty-five the Duchess of
Roxburghe is in absolute possession of
$30,000,000 of New York real estate.
One of her earliest suitors was the
Duke of Manchester. His engagement
was actually announced by the Lon
don "Daily Telegraph." Mr. Ogden
Goelet, who was then alive, told a re
porter that he could never allow his
daughter to marry a foreigner. It was
later learned that Miss Goelet had vol
untarily declined the Duke. After that
he c'onsoled himself for a time with
journalism and next year eloDed with
Miss Zimmerman of Cincinnati a mar
riage which has turned out cuite hao
pily. Miss Goelet had suitors in the highest
society of every European country.
There was Prince Henri of Orleans, by
far the most enterprising member of
the dethroned royal family of France.
He thought that Miss Goelet's $30,000,
000 would help the royalist cause, but
he sought it in vain. Then he tried
to win fame as an explorer and died
miserably in Tonkin.
The most illustrious of all by birth
was the Grand Duke Boris, first cousin
of the Czar of Russia. When he was
staying with the Goelets at Newport
Mrs. Stuyvesant Fish remarked that
"everybody knew he was there to mar
ry Miss Goelet and pay off his debts."
A most interesting suitor in France
was the brilliant Paul Deschanel, now
President of the Chamber of Deouties
and regarded as the next President of
the republic. He needed a rich wife
badly in his political career, but he
failed to win Miss Goelet.
Jacques Lebaudy, who is as rich as
Miss Goelet, being the son of the great
est sugar refiner in France, has re
cently created himself Emperor of the
Sahara. Miss Goelet might have been
Empress.
In Italy an exalted suitor was the
Duke of Abruzzi, cousin of the Kine:
of Italy. When he found that there
was no hope for him he organized an
expedition to the North Pole and scored
the farthest North.
</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1904-08-27/ed-1/?sp=19&q=Minnie_Stevens+Arthur+Paget+English+Royalty+American+Queen+Dame</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1904-10-16/ed-1/?sp=17&q=American+Heiresses+Titles+British+Peerage+Duke+Richmond+Marquis+Bute&r=-0.001,-0.052,0.829,0.344,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1910-03-27/ed-1/?sp=16&q=Drexel+Drexels+Titled+Husband+Duke+Duchess+Marlborough+Viscount+Maidstone&r=-0.429,0.243,1.367,0.566,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Mr. Drexel COUld do was to make It
clear to the nobleman that he did not In
tend to leave his daughter's happiness at
her husband's mercy; that he did not pro
pose to give his lordship an enormous
income with which to amuse himself Just
as he pleased.
The winning and Ingenuous young Eng
lishman protested that money was the
last thing he desired. All he asked was
the privilege of adoring her. This gaYS
Mr. Drexel his opportunity.
Then and there he proposed n formal
contract regulating the futuro life ami
Income of the young couple—a contract
that was reully an elaborate system of
rtwardS and punishments.
This marriage settlement provides that
the first year the pair shall have a Joint
income of Jo.niiO a year, the second year
$10,000, the third year 115,000, and so on In
an ascending scale up to $50,000 a year.
The sum of $5,000 for tire first year and
the Increased allowance for several sub-
Sequent years will be available as pocket
money for ihe young couple. It has been
announced that they will make their horns
at first In the London house of Mr. and
Mrs. Drexel nt No. 22 Qrosvenor Square.
Thus they will bo practically free from
housekeeping expenses.
This arrangement by Itself fully con
firms tiie statement that the young couple
are to live at first on a very moderate
Income
The marriage settlement further pro
vides that the allowance is only to re
main In force as long as V iscount Maid-
Btoue bs&aves himself properly, and does
A GERMAN engineer has just In- makes fair progr.li OV.r goed, roads
vented and patented a sailing and across sandy stretches, sueli as a
vessel for uso on highways, sea beach. The dominating features In
i .fc-i- »,_« Realising the lmportnnco of the wind tha construction are lightness and
not give his wife any ground for seeking of ,he family and a few generations spent the greater part Of th.lr tlCßfl to oron ut an d tha mariner, tho effsatlVS steering facilities,
even a separation. later the two titles became merged In the abroad for fifteen years. </text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-12-24/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Titles+American+Marriages+Duke+Duchess+Earl+Viscount+Consuelo+Vanderbilt+Heiresses+Heiress+International+Marriage</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The ti'ee may be said to have taken
its -real start in 1895, or about that
time. It was then that Consuelo,
daughter of William K. Vanderbilt,
became the duchess :of Marlborough.
To be sure, she was the second Amer
ican girl to bear that title, the eighth
duke having married Lillian, daughter
of Commander; Price, U.S. N., and
widow of Louis Hammersley of. New
York, but the circumstances of this
union: attracted far more attention than
any International marriage had yet
done. Both; were young and an enor
mous fortune and a splendid name and
estate were Joined together with daz
zling, possibilities</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1913-09-28/ed-1/?sp=33&q=Heiress+Title+Hunter+International+Marriages+Marriage+Baron+Titled+American+Girl</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>I am convinced that American
heiresses marry foreigners for love
In nine cases out of ten. The glamor
of a title may have something to do with attracting
an heiress, and arouse in her a sense of justifiable
feminine curiosity to see what the owner and wearer
of the dignity Is like, but rarely does it influence her
seriously in making the final choice- It would be
charitable, but misleading, to attribute this to some
special moral fibre In the American heiress when tho
fact is that she does not usually know what a title
means until she has been the part owner in one for
quite some time.
Outside of the title there are potent reasons why
the American heiress prefers the' foreigner to her
countryman' With her unschooled feminine intuition
she Is quick to see the decisive divergences between
the aristocrat and the plutocrat</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1919-01-16/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Future+Queen+King+Prince+Wales+Princess+Princesses&r=-0.514,0.048,2.028,0.84,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1919-12-21/ed-1/?sp=39&q=Lady+Astor+Langhorne+Lord+American+Women+Parliament+Viscount+Waldorf</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&date1=1756&date2=1963&proxtext=Trial+of+Lizzie+Borden&x=22&y=14&dateFilterType=yearRange&rows=20&searchType=basic</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1937-04-24/ed-1/seq-31/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Borden+Lizzie+Trial+trial&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Lizzie+Borden+Trial+&y=14&x=16&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016399/1893-06-16/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=Borden+Lizzie+trial&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Trial+of+Lizzie+Borden&y=14&x=22&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>The evidence against Lizzie
Borden on the third day of the trial was
weak
Testimony for the
prosecution was continued in the trial of
Lizzie Borden for murder at New Bedford,
Mass</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84022549/1893-06-15/ed-1/seq-10/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=Borden+Lizzie+Trial+trial&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Trial+of+Lizzie+Borden&y=14&x=22&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>GUILTY OR NOT?
Progress of the Trial of Lizzie Borden at
Fall Klver.
' The trial of Lizzie Borden, charged
with the murder of her father and
mother, is progressing slowly. So far
the state has put in a large amount of
testimony, some of an apparently dam
aging nature to the defendant, but the
rigid cross-examinations by ex-Gov. Rob
inson nave changed the color oi the tes
timony and show that much of it was
manufactured. Witnesses dispute each
otherand even refute their own testimony
from day to day. Jt is generally con
ceded that the state's case is being
weakened by each additional witness.
The testimony for the state is now about
all in, and the case will probably go to
the jury by Saturday. The testimony
extracted by the coroner's jury from
Miss Borden just after the murder, when
she was nearly insane with grief and
from the effects of drags, was excluded,
as it should be. It is doubtful if the de
fense puts in many witnesses, and
whether Miss Borden goes on the stand.
At present, it looks as though the jury
will bring in a verdict of acquittal with
out a wrangle.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92064044/1893-06-16/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=Borden+Lizzie+trial+trials&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Trial+of+Lizzie+Borden&y=14&x=22&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>The trial of Lizzie Borden at New Bed
ford is engrossing the attention of news
paper readers throughout the country.
Thus far the prosecution have put in a
very weak case and the prevailing opinion
seems to be that the prisoner will be
acquitted.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id><https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87080287/1893-06-15/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=Borden+Lizzie+trial&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Trial+of+Lizzie+Borden&y=14&x=22&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1/id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>The arguments on the introduc
tion of Lizzie Borden's testimony at the
inquest were begun nnd a critical stage of
the trial reached 
he evi
-1 dence given by Lizzie Borden at the cor
-1 oner's inquest at Fall River was excluded
in her trial at New Bedford, and it is
said that she will give testimony later</text>
      </result>
     </results> 
  </topic>
  <topic>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&date1=1756&date2=1963&proxtext=Chinese+Exclusion+act&x=18&y=14&dateFilterType=yearRange&rows=20&searchType=basic</id>
  <results>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015409/1943-12-05/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Act+Chinese+Exclusion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Chinese+Exclusion+act&y=14&x=18&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>LABOR’S SUPPORT PLEDG
ED — Caught in this inform
al pose as they chatted during
a lull in convention proceedings
are James B. Carey, national
secretary-treasurer of the CIO,
Vice President Wallace and the
organization’s liberal and
dynamic president, Philip
Murray. CIO pledged $700,
000 for political action; adopt
ed unanimously a non-strike
pledge “for the duration of the
war” and blazed the way to
democracy by adopting a reso
lution proposed by Willard
Townsend urging the repeal of
the Chinese Exclusion Act,
which rs significant because of
its importance to all minorities.</text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90065065/1905-08-05/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=act+Chinese+exclusion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Chinese+Exclusion+act&y=14&x=18&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>American Goods Will Be Shut Ont of
Celestial Empire if Chinese Exclu
sion Act is Not Repealed at Once.
From the Skagway Ahakaa.
SHANGHAI,^ July 21.-The heads of
the Chinese guilds, in session is this
city, agreed yesterday to enforce * boy
cott against goods manufactured in the
United States. They will try to eon
pel the American government to repeal
the obnoxious restrictions to Chinees
entrance to that country. The utter
ances of American statesmen in favor
of St more liberal interpretation of the
.Chinese exclusion act have enco
the hope that niwai -wBl follow the
boycott* .</text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/46032385/1901-11-29/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=act+Act+Chinese+exclusion+Exclusion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Chinese+Exclusion+act&y=14&x=18&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>The Chinese Exclusion Act.
The republican positiononcern4ngthp Chinese,
exclusion act is well illustrated by-an (editorial
appearing in the Lincoln (Neb.) Journal of Novem
ber 17. The Journal anticipates that the presl- ,.
dent sis about to recommend the re-enactment of
the Chinese exclusion act, and lest it might bo
out of the republican line, it hastens to commend
the president's conclusion on this point. And yet,
having anticipated the president's, position, the
Journal expresses this opinion:
Still it is doubtful if a "referendum" was
taken under the Australian ballot system, the
question of exclusion coming up independently
of politics, if the exclusion act would be sus- ,
tained. The coolie is an exceedingly useful
person to have around when laborers afe scarce
and their terms exorbitant or unreasonable.
The domestic service problem Is getting to be
a pressing one and the coolie offers 'a sort of
solution.
Then this thoroughly representative newspa
per says:
But if the labor problem becomes in the
course of time more difficult, as it promises to
become if the extreme theories of the unions
are carried out, and it is a square contest be
tween the labor unions and the rest of the pop
ulation, the act will one day be repealed as a
matter of necessity.
This, then, may be said to be the republican
position concerning the Chinese exclusion act.
The exclusion act should not be re-enacted, ac-r
cording to the republican idea, but political ex
pediency may require its re-enactment. It is also
instructive to be told by the republican organs
that "if the labor problem becomes in the course
of time more difficult, as it promises to become If
the extreme theories of the unions are carried
out, and it is a square contest between the labor
unions and the rest of the population, the act -will
one day be repealed as-a matter of necessity.</text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1943-05-30/ed-1/seq-73/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=act+Chinese+exclusion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Chinese+Exclusion+act&y=14&x=18&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>Pcorl Buck meets some warm supporters Outside the House Immigration Committee room, where she had just urged repeal of the Chinese exclusion
act, the author of Chinese novels receives the thanks of a group of young Chinese women. Miss Buck toid the committee the Japanese are using the
exclusion act in their counter propaganda in China</text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020662/1943-11-22/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=act+Chinese+exclusion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Chinese+Exclusion+act&y=14&x=18&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>The second move to cut out a
Jap propaganda cancer came
when, with Administration urg
ing, the House Rules Committee
cleared the way for a vote on the
Magnuson bill, which would re
peal the Chinese exclusion act.
No single move by our govern
ment or statute on our books has
provided the Japanese with such
an effective propaganda weapon
as the act by which the Chinese,
out of all peoples in the world,
are forbidden entry to these
shores and of course denied the
nght of naturalized citizenship.
Both editorially here and
among supporters of the Magnu
son bill on the hill, the Chinese
exclusion act has been deplored
as one of the most antiquated and
unfair laws on the books. Its in
ception was. perhaps, almost a
humanitarian measure, for it
came when western employers
were importing Chinese coolies
by the boat load. They were vir
tually slave labor and in some
sections so upset wage scales as
to reduce Amerance labor to
pauperism.
Those were the lush days of
immigration. Immigration quotas
have been shaved and shaved un
til today, if the Magnuson bill
passes, as most observers are pos
itive it will, the Chinese under
present quotas could enter only
at the rate of 105 a year.</text>  
    </result>        
  </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&date1=1756&date2=1963&proxtext=Dollar+Princesses&x=0&y=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&rows=20&searchType=basic</id>
  <results>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1919-07-07/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Dollar+DOLLAR+Princesses+PRINCESSES&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Dollar+Princesses&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>0</rel>
  <text></text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085187/1916-07-10/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=dollar+princesses&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Dollar+Princesses&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>DOLLARS EARNED IN U. S.
PAY BRITISH WAR TAXES
Among (hi- former American women who carried fortunes to I h^i.iihl and now are ro|iiir<>(l
!<• help |iay John Hull's war expenses arc Mrs. \\ illi-im Ix'ods (loft ), l.u<ly ln-uc-. formerly YivUu
c.Mihl (center, uud .Mrs. O^den Mills (n^lii i.
By Mary Boyle O'Reilly
LONDON, July 10.—Ameririi's
"dollar princesses" who took
their dollar dowories to Kngland
when they married English no
blemen, and American wives of
Englishmen who are not nobles,
aro about to begin contributing
aproxiinatcly $1,000,000,000 .O
Johnny Bull to help defray the
expenses of war!
This contribution of Anierican
made dollars will not be made
with a smile.</text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1911-06-23/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=dollar+DOLLAR+princesses+PRINCESSES&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Dollar+Princesses&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>1</rel>
  <text>?
y aim*
wtn
Umbrokemi Ovation
ADD TO GLITTER
OF REGAL DISPLAY
American Peeresses Attract Nq
Little Attention in Scene
of Kingly Pomp.
THE "DOLLAR PRINCESSES''
Their Combined Wealth Equals
That of Entire English
Peerage.
(Special Cable to The TlmeB-Dlspatch.)
London. June 22.?Amid alt the
mediaeval pomp and splendor of the
English coronation, no small Interest
centred to-day In that small though
ever Increasing coterie of American
peeresses.' who added the glitter of
their splendid gems to those of their
foreign sisters, as they took their
scats in the great Abbey to watch the
ancient rites that formally place a
new King and .Queen over the United
Kingdom.
The American "dollar princesses,"
as thoy are called in England, now
number an even two dozen, and rep
?/?sent a combined wealth that equals,
If not overshadows, tbo aggregate
flnaaceB of tho entire English peerage,
the royal family excepted. In point of
rank, their number Is headed by the
Duchess of Marlborough, Consuelo
Vanderbllt, and ended by the Baroness
Lelth, of Fyvle, formerly Miss Jane
Garmany.</text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78000395/1911-07-01/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=dollar+Dollar+princesses+Princesses&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Dollar+Princesses&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>0</rel>
  <text></text>  
    </result>
    <result>
  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045396/1913-03-02/ed-1/seq-44/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=Dollar+Princesses&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Dollar+Princesses&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
  <rel>0</rel>
  <text></text>  
    </result>        
  </results>
  </topic>
</topics>

